In today's video, I'm going to try and play a record
在今天的节目中，我将给大家带来的是
that's made out of chocolate.
播放巧克力做的唱片
Now a bit of backstory on this.
现在我来说点幕后故事
I won't take too long out of your day though, but going back perhaps five
这事距离现在并没有那么远，但也有五六年了
years or so ago, I read an article about a lady who was based in Tasmania,
那时，我读了篇文章，说塔斯曼尼亚那里有一位
Bon Scott: Whole Lotta Roise is about an big fat Tasmanian woman called Roise.
a French artist who was making records out of chocolate that you could play.
法国女艺术家，她可以用巧克力做一个可以播放的唱片
I looked into getting hold of one.
当时我就想搞一个回来
But it didn't seem possible as a kind of mail-order type thing.
但是这个看上去不能网上预订
I think you have to actually go there and go in a workshop and
我觉得你得实际走一趟，去那个工坊
make your own that kind of stuff.
然后按照自己的想法去做
But it was an idea I kept in the back of my head thinking one day, maybe I'll
但我一直有这个念想，也许我
be able to play a chocolate record.
可以播放一个巧克力唱片
Anyway, a few weeks ago I was looking for something on Etsy
然后呢，几周前我在Etsy上找些东西
注：etsy.com是个卖手工艺品的网站
and it just popped into my mind.
这玩意就又跳入我的视野中了
I thought, well, there's loads of people on there that make stuff like that.
我想：“好吧，没想到真的有很多人制作这些东西呢。”
Did a search.
我搜索了一下
Yeah, sure enough.
当然，你们也猜到了
There's a lady in the UK, a chocolatier who makes all sorts of weird and
注：Chocolatier应该是巧克力艺术家的意思吧
在英国有个艺术家，她经常用巧克力
fanciful things out of chocolate.
制作一些奇怪的，富有想像力的艺术品
One of which was a playable chocolate record.
而这其中就有一个可以播放的巧克力唱片
So of course I ordered one.
很自然地，我预购了一张
and here it is.
这个就是啦
Now, the thing with this is once it arrived, I then thought, hold on a
然而拿到货的时候，我就想
minut, how am I going to play this?
等会，我拿嘛玩意播放这个？
Obviously on a record player, but my decent record player?
很明显要用唱片机播放，但是我用不用我平常用的唱机呢？
Well, I don't really want to damage the stylus on that or the cartridge.
实际上，我并不想因为播放这个而把唱针给搞坏
I mean, it costs a few hundred quid, I think, I looked around the house,
因为我花了好几千呢，所以我找遍了屋子
trying to find a suitable record player and my eye came across this one.
想找到一些合适的唱片机，然后我找到了这个
You might remember this record player made a few years ago, a kind of
你也许记得这种几年前生成的机器
cardboard box, basic type of thing.
纸盒子包装，并且有一些基本功能
Don't mind if this one gets ruined.
坏了我不在乎
So I put my chocolate record on this record player, and this is what happened.
所以我把巧克力唱片放了上去，然后就......
Whoops.
:-P
Yeah.
好吧
So that was a bit of a shame, but it's entirely my fault.
确实有点遗憾哈，但这全是我的错
I was just using the wrong kind of record player.
我用错唱片机了
These kinda things, you know, like the suitcase ones, the Crosleys, all that
我平常用的，诸如便携式的啊，Crosleys牌的啊
kind of stuff, with their sapphire stylus.
他们都是配有蓝宝石唱针的
It's just too much downward force.
这种唱针下压力十分地大
So rather than following the groove, that's in the chocolate, it just drew
所以唱针就不随着巧克力唱片上的刻纹走了
its own spiral into it after all is quite soft, but that means it's now
它直接就划伤唱片了，毕竟这玩意十分的软
unplayable on anything, which is.
所以这个现在就放不了了
unfortunate because this cost 26 pound, it's 20 pounds plus six pound
有点小遗憾，因为这个花了我26英镑呢
注：1英镑约合9元人民币
delivery they're made to order.
其中包括6英镑运费
They take about two to three weeks to be delivered handmade.
他们寄出去之前要花三四周来做这个
You get your own information printed on the middle here on some
这个唱片中间印着你想印上去的信息
sort of edible paper type stuff.
像是用某种可食用纸做的
You got a choice of two tracks you can have on these.
你可以让他们在这个上面刻上两首歌
It plays I believe, a short snippet.
应该是两小段音乐吧
If I could get it to play, out of, We Wish You a Merry Christmas or Happy Birthday,
如果我能播放出来的话，那应该是We Wish You a Merry Christmas或者是生日快乐歌
depending upon which one you choose.
取决于你当时的选择
And they're played by the Tewksbury Town Band.
这应该是Tewksbury Town Band表演的
So if I could play it, I'll be able to play to you and we wouldn't hit a
所以如果我能播放这个的话，你们就能欣赏了
content match on a chocolate record.
而且这上面就没有划痕了
So all a bit disappointing, really.
所以总体来说，有点小失望
Uh, so, so I  thought I can't leave it there.
但是，这计划不能到此就烂尾了
I ordered another one and here it is.
我又买了一份，这就是了
Take two.
第二版:-P
So this one I'm going to play it properly or at least try to, rather than play on
这个呢，我尽量要合理地播放它，而不是
something that's just going to ruin it.
在不合适的机器上播放，把它给毁了
I'm going to use a turntable that has a much lighter tracking force and I'm also
我将使用一个 turntable 唱片机，这个针压会很小
going to adjust it back a little bit.
并且我还要将针往后放一下
So it's got an even lighter tracking force than normal.
这样的话，针压就会更小了
So let me show you which one I'm going to use.
现在我来展示一下我是怎么用的
I'm going to use this floating record player.
我将要用这个立式唱片机
Now this is something I reviewed quite a few years ago.
这台机器我几年前是用过的
I'm not sure they even make these anymore, but the reason I'm using this one is,
我不知道这个现在还能不能用，但是我用这个的原因
its sat unused since I made that video.
是因为这个自打上次做完视频后就一直搁置着
And yet it's got a pretty decent cartridge on here.
而且呢，这个唱针看上去也很不错
An Audio-Technica AT95, and I've also put a little bit of a white tack stuff on the
这是个Audio-Technica AT95，我还唱臂的末端
end of the tone arm here, just to take a bit of weight off, a counterbalance.
放了一个白色的小钉子，这样针压能减轻些，这是重力平衡的缘故
So I'm hoping that this is going to work.
所以，我希望这个能用吧
If it doesn't  well, let's just give it up as a bad job after this one.
如果不能用的话，这个项目就只能烂尾了
So this is really my last attempt.
所以说，我就放手一搏了
So I've actually put this record in the fridge for a little bit this morning,
所以我在今天早晨将这个唱片放冰箱冷藏了一下
just to make it a little bit harder.
这样唱片就能硬一些了
You can see they're quite thick these as well.
你可以看出，这个东西已经很硬了
So that meant I couldn't use it in some of the turntables that have like
所以这东西我就不能用在有某些
a linear tracking thing with a lid on them because it wouldn't fit inside.
线性跟踪的唱盘了，上面有盖子的更不行了，因为根本就合不上
So this is about the best one I've got.
所以这个就是目前我能搞到最合适的了
I'm hoping it'll fit on there.
希望能合适地放在里面吧
There we go.
就这样
And not fall off.
没有掉下来
Okay.
好的
Are you ready?
准备好了吗
Let's uh, Oh, plays at 45 RPM by the way.
让我们......对了，唱片是45转的
So let's have a go.
咱现在来播放吧
They do say on the back of the box, there's no promises
他们盒子后面也说，他们对能不能播放
that you be able to hear it.
不能作出保证
It is just a bit of fun, but the audio is on there.
反正是放着玩，但是这上面是有音频的
So let's see if we can hear it.
那么，我们来看看能不能播放吧
So I'm not going to put it down right at the beginning in case it
这回我就不把唱针放在唱片开头了
does its own thing again, let's put it down in the middle somewhere.
唱针不讲武德地划伤唱片，我们把唱针放在中间某处
So here we go, fingers crossed.
好的，就这样，上帝保佑吧
I've got my volume turned up.
我把音量开到了最大
Yeah, I think I'm going to need to clean that stylus off,
好吧，也许我应该清理这个唱针了吧
but, wow that worked didn't it?
但是，这个居然能播放
I'm sure you could hear that quite clearly like I could.
你们应该和我一样地能听出来
It didn't too dissimilar to some old cylinders that I've got.
这个比那些最差的唱片更清楚
Really quite impressed how the stylus was able to follow the
我对唱针能够跟着唱片上的凹槽转
groove on the disc as well, because I can't feel it with my finger.
也十分地惊讶，因为我手指基本都感受不到凹槽
So it must be very fine, which is why you need a, a tonearm
所以说，这个播放质量一定会很好，只要你需要
with a very light tracking force.
一个下压力很低的唱臂就行了
Otherwise it's just going to ignore it and carve its own groove into it.
否则的话，唱针就不跟着凹槽走了，在巧克力唱片上留下划痕
But yeah, if you want to buy one of these, I'll put links in the video description.
如果你想要的话，我在下面会给链接的
Might be a bit too late for a Christmas gift for somebody, but
当然，这个当圣诞礼物还是太早了，但是
注：翻译视频时，VLC的路障已经有圣诞帽子了:-)
they do a birthday one as well.
当个生日礼物也挺好滴
But bear in mind, if you're buying it for someone, they're going to
但是要想好，如果你要给那个人买的话，他们家一定要有
have to have a record player with a light tracking force that they really
下压力比较小的唱片机，并且他们不介意
don't mind damaging the stylus on, although I'm sure this one's okay.
损耗一个唱针，虽然我这个可以用
Now this is a bit unusual.
这里我要插一句
So just on the off chance, if anyone out there wants to share this video
以防万一，如果有人想要分享这个视频
with anyone to say, Hey, look here's a chocolate record being played.
跟他们说，同志啊，这里有一个可以播放的巧克力唱片
I'm quite sure they're not interested in all the preamble at the beginning.
我很肯定他们对前面的长篇大论不感兴趣
So I'll do a specially edited version of this, that just
所以我特意剪了一个短点的视频
注：这个视频就是1P，相信各位都会来看完这个长篇的吧:-)
goes straight into the record.
直接就是放唱片
So they don't have to sit through all that mumbo-jumbo.
那么，他们就可以不用听我前面唠叨那么多了
But I think, we should just play this one out with the Tewksbury Town Band
最后，我们应该就放着这个由Tewksbury Town Band演奏的
and We Wish you a Merry Christmas.
We Wish you a Merry Christmas
And I suppose I wish you a Merry Christmas as well, after all it is
我希望大家圣诞节都快乐
SuperBart：大家冬至快乐，没冻掉耳朵吧:-)
now December when I'm recording this.
毕竟这个视频是在12月录制的
I was just tidying up and I realized there's one thing that I should
我刚才收拾的时候，意识到我应该
have done at the end of the video, which never came into my mind.
在视频结束的时候应该做点啥
And that's to eat the record, after all it is made out of chocolate.
我应该吃掉这个巧克力，毕竟这个是巧克力做的
The reason that I didn't think of it, is because I'm a Type 1 diabetic,
我之所以没有那么做，是因为我有一型糖尿病
注：这个是自身免疫病，所以必须终身注射胰岛素，比很多老先生得的二型糖尿病更惨
so I don't really eat chocolate and I don't have a sense of taste so
所以我忌讳吃巧克力，而且我不好这口
I can't tell you how good it is, but, um, we'll, uh, we'll try a bit
所以我也说不出个所以然，但是这回，我尝些吧
seems fine.
看上去还行
I mean, I'm sure it's very good chocolate, it's that kind of Belgian type chocolate.
我觉得，这个巧克力确实不错，比利时类型的巧克力
And that's the, uh, that's the label that's made out of, uh,
这个内标嘛，我觉应该是
like rice paper or something.
用米纸做的吧
So yeah, there you go.
好的，就是这样啦
Edible record.
可食用的唱片
You've heard it.
你听了它
I've ate a bit, now I'd best go and find my insulin.
我也吃了点，现在我要赶紧去打胰岛素了:-(
Anyway, that is definitely it for this one.
无论如何，本期节目就是这样啦
Thanks for watching.
感谢收看
感谢以下在Patreon支持我的人;-)
以下是精选评论
"You have good taste in music." versus "You have good tasting music." :D
“你的音乐品味真特别”亦可称为“你很喜欢吃音乐” :D
注：taste有味道和品味的意思
"Gosh, you've put on some weight!" "Well, I had a double album."
注：本意应为：我听了双唱片专辑
——天哪，你胖了那么多！ ——是啊，我吃了两个唱片
Should've sent it to LGR so he could do an food review.
应该给LGR寄一份，这样就可以做期美食评测了
next day headline: "Techmoan hospitalized after eating record"
转一天的头条新闻：Techmoan由于吃唱片住院
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者Techmoan发布于2020-12-12